A Guide to the Robert A. Brock Miscellaneous files, 1655-1908
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Robert A. Brock Miscellaneous files, 1655-1908
The Library of Virginia
41008
51 reels.
Robert Alonzo Brock
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Robert Alonzo Brock Collection was filmed by The Huntington Library in cooperation with The Library of Virginia with funding provided by The Library of Virginia Foundation with the support of The Roller-Bottimore Foundation and The Robins Foundation. Microfilm received April 2005.
Biographical Information
Robert Alonzo Brock, historian, antiquarian, and collector, was born in Richmond, Virginia in 1839. At the outbreak of the Civil War he enlisted in the 21st Virginia Regiment, transferring later to a hospital unit with which he remained for the duration of the war. Brock later served as associate editor of the Richmond Standard (1879-1882), corresponding secretary of the Virginia Historical Society (1875-1892), and secretary of the Southern Historical Society (1887-1914). He also edited the societies' papers and authored the first biographical dictionary of Virginians (Virginia and Virginians). An avid collector of Virginiana, Brock started his collection before the Civil War and added materials up to the time of his death in 1914, accumulating nearly 50,000 manuscripts relating to Virginia and the history of the South.
Scope and Content
The Robert Alonzo Brock miscellaneous files, 1655-1908, include a wide variety of business, organizational, personal, and military records collected by Brock. The records encompass not only Virginia, but many other East coast colonies and states. The files are organized chronologically and cover a variety of topics, locations, and time periods. Included are accounts, affidavits, agreements, bills, bonds, correspondence, deeds, inventories, invitations, petitions, power of attorney, promissory notes, receipts, reports, surveys, reports, and warrants.
Topics include agriculture, business, genealogy, politics, social life, universities, and war. The collection encompasses such a wide range of materials, a separate database was created to identify each manuscript. In order to access the collection, patrons should search the database for specific names or topics.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Location of Originals
Originals located at the Henry E. Huntington Library, San Marino, California.
Contents List
- Robert A. Brock Miscellaneous Files, 1655-1908. (Reel 5056-5106)
  - 1655-1753., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5056, Box 256)
  - 1755-1771., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5057, Box 257)
  - 1772-1778., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5058, Box 258)
  - 1781-1786., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5059, Box 259)
  - 1787-1792., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5060, Box 260)
  - 1793-1798., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5061, Box 261)
  - 1799-1802., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5062, Box 262)
  - 1803-1809., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5063, Box 263)
  - 1810-1814., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5064, Box 264)
  - 1815-1818., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5065, Box 265)
  - 1819-1822., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5066, Box 266)
  - 1823-1826., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5067, Box 267)
  - 1827-1831., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5068, Box 268)
  - 1832-1835., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5069, Box 269)
  - 1836-1838., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5070, Box 270)
  - 1839-1841., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5071, Box 271)
  - 1842-1844., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5072, Box 272)
  - 1845-1847., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5073, Box 273)
  - 1848-1850., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5074, Box 274)
  - 1851-1852., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5075, Box 275)
  - 1853-1854., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5076, Box 276)
  - 1855., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5077, Box 277)
  - 1856-1857., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5078, Box 278)
  - 1858-1859., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5079, Box 279)
  - 1860., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5080, Box 280)
  - 1861 January 28 - October 30., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5081, Box 281)
  - 1861 November 1 - December 31., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5082, Box 282)
  - 1862 January 2 - August 28., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5083, Box 283)
  - 1862 September 2 - December 31., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5084, Box 284)
  - 1863 January 2 - August 26., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5085, Box 285)
  - 1863 September 10 - December 31., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5086, Box 286)
  - 1864 January 3 - August 29., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5087, Box 287)
  - 1864 September 1 - December 31., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5088, Box 288)
  - 1865 January 2 - July 31., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5089, Box 289)
  - 1865 August 3 - December 31., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5090, Box 290)
  - 1866., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5091, Box 291)
  - 1867., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5092, Box 292)
  - 1868., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5093, Box 293)
  - 1869., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5094, Box 294)
  - 1870., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5095, Box 295)
  - 1871., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5096, Box 296)
  - 1872-1873., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5097, Box 297)
  - 1874., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5098, Box 298)
  - 1875., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5099, Box 299)
  - 1876., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5100, Box 300)
  - 1877-1878., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5101, Box 301)
  - 1879-1881., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5102, Box 302)
  - 1882-1885., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5103, Box 303)
  - 1886-1888., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5104, Box 304)
  - 1889-1892., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5105, Box 305)
  - 1893-1908., Extent: 1 reel. (Reel 5106, Box 306)